It took some work, but the renovations were finally completed.
And with that, it was time to begin preparations for this world's wedding-slash-housewarming custom.
A.K.A. a reception.
All right, Sylphie. Let's go over this guest list one last time.
Right.
Here we go.
We have Alina, Lise, Zanoba, Julie, and Cliff.
Linia, Persina, King Body, Vice Principal Genius, and Soldot.
Then Princess Ariel, her two attendants, and Luke.
I'd love to invite my family, but they're just too far away.
I sent Paul a letter, at least.
But who knows how long it will take to reach him.
Hang on. You're still missing Nana Hoshi.
Yeah, I'm not so sure she'd come.
Well, I know she would.
Okay, I'll ask her and see.
But, uh, what if we do all this prep work and no one shows up?
I can promise you that Princess Ariel and Zanoba will be there.
And I bet Linia and Persina will come as well.
They'd never refuse an invite from their boss, now would they?
And I guess Cliff would come, since he specifically asked.
Personally, I'm hoping Alina Lise can join us.
There's something I've been meaning to ask her.
It's not really a big deal.
Really? I wonder what that could be.
I've barely even seen them in the same room together.
And I'll see you later.
Bye.
Now, with 10 plus guests attending this thing, we'll need to serve up quite a meal.
So it's time for a little shopping trip.
Before we get groceries, I'd like to buy you some new clothes.
Good idea. I am kind of attached to these, but they've gotten pretty shabby.
Clothes shopping it is. Dress me up however you like.
I won't let you down.
Would you be able to help us pick out a new set of mage's robes for him?
Certainly. If I may ask, then, what particular schools of magic do you favor?
Oh, uh, just water and earth, I suppose.
Excellent. This one is quite water-resistant. This one is ideal for earth magic.
I'm not sure. What do you like better, Sylphie?
Actually, I'm fond of this one. And it's not too different from the one you have now.
That robe is comprised largely of the pelt of the Lucky Rat from the Demon Continent.
It's a Khazra design, highly resistant to both poison and acid.
They do say names count for a lot. Guess we'll go with this.
That is not a price I associate with clothes. Imported goods don't come cheap.
If the name is what you like, good sir, do forgive me, but may I ask for yours?
Oh, yeah. My name is Rudeus Greyrat.
You don't say. I didn't realize you were a grey rat.
Well, Lord Luke has been generous in his patronage to my shop.
Please allow me to offer you a discount.
We bought a lot of stuff today. Makes sense, though. Big house needs a lot of stuff.
If money gets tight, I could go back to adventuring. Nah, and get myself killed.
You're not worried about the money, are you? We will be fine, Rudy. I've been saving my wages from Princess Ariel.
I know. It just makes me feel so useless.
And leave the cooking to me, okay? I learned from your mom and Lilia, and I want to show off.
Well, I wonder if it'll suit your tastes.
For you, my love, I'd call charcoal delicious.
Have a little faith. I mean, honestly, who do you think I spent all that time learning to cook for?
Oh, Sylphiette, you're such a perfect bride. I can't help but feel nervous that I'm not worthy of you.
Of course you are, silly. You're my ideal husband, too, you know.
Rudeus, I love you.
Uh-oh.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, what are you?
Oh, God.
Jeez.
A few days later, it was time for the reception.
We picked a day during our monthly break, noon sharp.
Genius excused himself, and Soldot said he was too busy.
Badigati said he'd come, which surprised me.
The other 11 invites were all accepted.
Yes, even Nana Hoshi came to join us.
Well, this is rare. Weird to see you outside your tower.
You're the one who invited me.
Yep, and I'm very glad you could make it.
We've got some potato chips and stuff for you.
Really? Did you make them?
Of course, because thanks to you, we were able to get a hold of cooking oil.
Where are they?
Rudy, everything's ready.
Oh, and we told our guests the truth about silent fits.
Okay, now we're just waiting on Badigati.
People who live for millennia have no concept of how time passes.
You can probably expect them to arrive a month or so from now.
Yeah, best to go ahead and get started then.
Sorry, Badigati.
You can do it.
Thank you all for joining us today.
We know you're busy and we're so glad you came.
The occasion is no secret, but, um, just to say it officially, Sylphie and I...
Enter the Demon King, Badigati, with us a bang!
Badigati, you're a little late, you know.
Ah, that is where you are wrong.
Among my people, royals arrive when least expected, so as to astound and astonish the masses.
Thus, I am right on time.
You're joking.
No, it's true.
I went quite out of my way on your account, young gray rat.
You ought to be grateful.
Sure, thank you, sire.
Now then, as I was saying, thank you for taking time out of your busy lives for us.
And as you know, Sylphiet and I are to be married.
We know that we're still young, but we hope for a fruitful life together.
Those of you gathered today have been especially close to us during our time here, so, um...
Ah, crap, that was way too stiff and formal, wasn't it?
I'm making this awkward.
No need to stand on ceremony, young man.
You two love each other, do you not?
Simply allow us all to celebrate that love together.
Hmm.
Basically that.
We're starting a life together, so...
We hope you'll all stay a part of it.
Thanks!
And now, a toast to the young couple's future!
Cheers, everyone!
Sylphie, congratulations!
Thank you so very much!
Now pray tell, do your home and husband meet your expectations, my dear?
Both better than I ever dared to dream.
Did I tell you we even have a bath here?
You know, we could arrange for you to take a year off from being my bodyguard if you would like that.
Um, not yet, but if we have children...
Please don't tease me, your highness!
Well, I figure you still don't like me that much, but...
Let's try to get along.
I know I don't have any hang-ups...
Sounds good.
I'd like that, Luke.
Hello, Grandmaster and Mrs. Grandmaster.
Thank you for inviting me today.
And from the bottom of our hearts, warm congratulations.
Thank you both, really.
And you, fair lady.
How could I have mistaken my master's wife for a man?
I hope you can forgive my rudeness all this time.
Oh, gosh.
You don't have to bow to me.
Rudy mistook me for a man before.
Twice even.
Right?
Embarrassing as it is to admit it.
Yes, yes, I did.
Cubans don't normally stand around and yap at each other in the middle of a meal, do they?
Yeah, mind your manners.
She sat around a mouthful of food.
Thank you both so much for coming today.
Absolutely, like I was ever going to miss watching Silent Fitz and the Boss tie the knot.
Yeah, I always figured Fitz was a woman.
Pretty obvious to anyone within smell and distance.
Anyway, it's always good to see strong people get together, meow.
That's for sure.
Having strong children brings tranquility to the tribe.
Sure, that's one way to put it.
Why not?
Congrats.
Thank you.
Wait, Nana Hoshi?
Can I ask you something?
I suppose.
One time, you said that you and Rudy come from the same place.
Tell me, what do you mean?
Since he can speak my language, I just assumed.
Oh God, grant them eternal love and gift them with bountiful fortune.
Best prayer I've got, I humbly bless your marriage.
Thank you so much.
Rudeus, your manhood is back.
Congratulations.
I would have preferred to hear it from you, so don't hesitate to tell me next time.
Why, so you could ask if I was telling the truth and jump my bones to make me prove it?
No thanks.
That's not fair.
Remember what I told you?
I have no intention of becoming the daughter-in-law of Mr. Paul Greyrat.
Sylphiette, I'm happy for you, dear.
Thanks, that means a lot.
And I wish you both happy, happiness with all my...
I'm so sorry.
I don't know what's come over me.
What's wrong?
Are you okay?
Um, Alina Lise, do you feel sad because there's a chance you could be my grandma?
According to my father, my grandmother went on many adventures with Paul Greyrat.
No, that's not true.
I doubt any grandmother of yours would be a whore like me.
I heard my dad got chased out of the Great Forest because of it.
Apparently, he had trouble marrying, too.
I was hoping there'd be a connection.
What little he told me seemed to have fit you well.
I thought it might be you.
Well, you see...
Oh, uh...
Well, please forgive me.
I'm sorry.
They're related?
I'm starting to think it's not a coincidence that the pendant Sylphie made me look like Alina Lises.
And yeah, their faces are so similar.
Master Cliff?
Yes?
What is it?
Could you help Alina Lise to a room upstairs so she can have some privacy?
Yes.
Right away.
I think we should wait to have this conversation until she's had some time to rest.
Yes, of course.
Rudeus, I...
I know who I can be, but Lass didn't have the same predilections.
It's true, and neither does his daughter Sylphie.
So please...
You don't have anything to worry about.
I would never leave Sylphiette just because she's related to you.
But...
Not to mention, if I were you, I'd be a lot more concerned about the fact that you're about to be related to Paul.
Rudy, you picked a hell of a time to be a wisecrack.
Bye, Meow. Don't forget to be happy.
Man, you really are the boss of the school. No butts about it.
I can't wait for the next term.
I should get going. I'll have more experiments for you tomorrow.
Perhaps... I could come and use your bath from time to time?
Oh, Master, are you okay?
Uh, it appears I got a bit too carried away.
Those are weak words, even for a blessed child.
Ow! Ow!
Hey, Cliff, could Grandma...
I mean, Alina, Lisa and I have a moment to speak in private, please?
That okay?
Yes, I'll be fine.
Thank you, Cliff, Rudy.
Hey, Rodius, will they be alright?
If not, you and I are here to smooth things over.
Mr. Greyrat, thank you for inviting us here today.
Please, thank you for joining us.
Not to pry, but what's become of Sylphie?
She's speaking with Alina Lisa at the moment.
Ah, yes, I see. What perfect timing.
May I steal you for a few minutes, then?
Mr. Greyrat, this may sound impertinent,
but could you be troubled to agree to duel Luke?
No magic.
Strictly sword against sword.
Rest assured, this is all in good fun.
Oh, sure. All in good fun.
Then you wouldn't mind if we use fake swords, right?
If you'd like to conjure a sword with magic, I wouldn't object.
Yeah, but even if I were to do that,
Luke could still slice me clean in two.
I don't get it.
Why are they trying to rush me into a duel?
Have I done something to offend you, princess?
Hardly.
It's just a challenge you're free to refuse.
However,
I do hope you're inclined to accept.
Rudeus.
Accept.
Very well.
Begin!
You got lucky!
No!
We're done.
Enough!
Come on!
Elemois.
A healing spell.
How's your hand?
Are you alright?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Take good care of Sylvie.
I mean it.
On my life, of course.
But is there a reason you chose today of all days to challenge me to a duel?
There's not much to it, really.
Sylvie is very dear to us.
We've bonded through the course of our perilous travail, so forgive us, please.
Consider this duel a matter of personal pride and assurances.
I guess they wanted to find out if they can trust me with Sylvie's life.
Can't say I blame them.
I will make my return to Asura someday.
When I do, I will claim the throne, or die trying.
It is my right, my duty.
But Sylvie has no obligation to accompany me.
She is neither royalty nor nobility.
We were merely brought together by the mass teleportation.
Moreover, it's not my duty to presume on her.
So it's time I let her go to choose her own path.
It won't take long, you see.
Once she has a child, her desire to join us should fade of its own accord.
If she fails to move on, I'm leaving it up to you to step in and talk some sense into her.
That's a big ask.
I'm also in the princess's debt.
If I'm not careful, I'll end up wanting to tag along too.
Make no mistake.
If you fail to give our Sylvie the life she deserves, we will take her back, no question.
You have my word, princess.
Oh, Rudy, where's the princess?
I'm afraid you just missed her.
So Luke challenged Rudeus to a duel out of nowhere.
But Rudeus didn't back down.
He won no problem.
Did you?
Uh, yeah, I think that about sums it up.
Were you two able to finish your talk?
Yep.
It sounds like Alina Lise is Sylvie's grandmother after all.
Between her curse and her personality, she was never far from trouble.
So even when she had kids, she kept her real identity a secret.
And once they got old enough to fend for themselves, she disappeared.
All to protect them.
She pegged Sylvie as a descendant the moment she laid eyes on her.
But revealing herself never crossed her mind.
Until she saw Sylvie beaming with joy and became flooded with emotions.
Rudeus, I have a confession.
It's Lise.
She's not the person I thought she was.
Oh, yeah?
And?
Finally disillusioned, huh?
His crush not only has kids, but grandkids.
That had hit me pretty hard, too.
She's more sensitive than I could ever know.
The poor thing.
I swear I'll lift her curse.
But to make sure I get the job done right, I'd like your help.
So you didn't feel disillusioned after finding out who she really was?
Disillusioned?
Of course not.
Why would you even think that?
As my faith teaches, no matter her circumstances, whether our ideals clash, I have a duty to make
the woman who loves me as happy as she can be.
Because I've fallen in love with her as well.
I understand.
If there's any way I can help, allow me to assist.
Rude, please.
I thought we were friends now.
Stop being so formal.
I refuse.
Rudy, I've been thinking.
I'd like to grow my hair out.
Are you quite certain?
You are always being so formal.
My hair isn't green anymore, so I might as well.
I'll work hard so your love for me stays strong.
I promise.
How did I get so lucky?
She's gonna make me cry.
I'll work hard to keep her love for me strong, too.
Hey, Sylphie.
Thanks for everything today.
Oh, of course.
Thank you.
La-ya-la-ya-la